翻譯:張倩茜
OCR:微博@Emtee
“漢克葛林全球投資”
“美國紐約市百老街230號”
混蛋
Son of a bitch!
“年度最佳業務員 比爾莫里斯”
救命解藥
翻譯:張倩茜
我們不能動市政債券
No, we can't touch the munis.
我們要利用這些債券
We'll use them as collateral for a leveraged
作為思科融資股權的擔保品
equity position in Cisco.
“預測報表 尋找更新”
然後把錢從第一銀行移到拜恩
Then I want you to take everything out of First National and move it over to Banyon.
等等 你是說達拉瓦?
Wait, you mean Delaware?
我以為那早就沒了
I thought that was dead.
重新啟動了
That's resurrected.
我們得漂白雷諾斯的帳戶
We need to clean up the Reynolds account...
以免洗錢防治單位的混蛋來調查
in case those fucks at AML decide to do their job.
你確定?
Are you sure about this?
不要用電郵聯絡
Nothing on email.
星期一把錢都挪回來
Move everything back on Monday.
你有在聽嗎?
You paying attention?
有 我有
Yeah, yeah, I am.
查票 -我不知道...
- Tickets? - I don't know if...
我正在傳數字過去
I'm sending the numbers through now.
那葛林怎麼辦?
What about Green?
拖延他 誰管啊 必要就請病假
Uh, stall him. I don't give a shit. Call in sick if you have to.
你是洽公還是旅遊?
Business or pleasure?
我不知道．..
I don't know. I just...
你認真的?
Seriously?
我不知道這樣好不好...
Look, I don't know if I feel comfortable...
賈許 別再孬了
Josh! Josh! Stop being such a pussy.
照表說的去辦 完成後打給我
Just do what I tell you to do, and call me when it's done.
致董事會同仁
To my fellow members of the board.
“2016年7月18日”
人無法忽視真相
A man cannot unsee the truth.
一旦看見光明
He cannot willingly return to darkness...
就不可能自願回歸黑晴或選擇失明
or go blind once he has the gift of sight...
就如同無法回到未出生時
any more than he can be unborn.
人類是唯一能自表反省的物種
We are the only species capable of self-reflection.
只有人類的基因密碼
The only species with the toxin of self-doubt
編寫了自我懷疑的毒素
written into our genetic code.
跟天賦不對等的是
Unequal to our gifts,
我們會創造、購買、消耗
we build, we buy, we consume.
我們以物質成功的假象包裝自我
We wrap ourselves in the illusion of material success.
我們欺騙隱瞞 一路往上爬
We cheat and deceive as we claw our way...
到達所謂成就的巔峰
to the pinnacle of what we define as achievement.
對其他人產生優越感
Superiority to other men.
角落辦公室
Corner office.
你是替誰吹喇叭換來的?
Who'd you have to blow?
我聽說他搞定了雷諾斯的帳戶
I heard he closed the Reynolds account.
你到底是怎麼辦到的?
How exactly did you do that?
算我實力堅強吧
Just that good, I guess.
別忘了我捫這些小咖
Don't forget about us little people.
我哪會
Oh, how could I?
你知道我的咖啡要加什麼
You know how I take my coffee.
抱歉 上頭請你到董事會議室
Excuse me, but they wanna see you upstairs in the partners boardroom.
跟他們說我馬上過去
Tell them I'll be right there.
明天是你媽的生日
Oh, and tomorrow is your mother's birthday.
替我買個禮物給她
Get her something for me, would you?
沒問題
Of course.
人的內在充滿病態
There is a sickness inside us.
就像膽汁竄升喉頭的苦澀味
Rising like the bile that leaves that bitter taste at the back of our throats.
正坐在桌旁的每個人都一樣
It's there in every one of you seated around the table.
我們否認病態存在
We deny its existence
直到有一天 身體背叛心靈
until one day the body rebels against the mind...
大聲呼喊著 我生病了
and screams out, "I am not a well man."
你當然一心只想著並購的事
No doubt you will think only of the merger.
兩個同等病態公司的齪齪結合
That unclean melding of two equally diseased institutions.
但事實不容忽視
But the truth cannot be ignored.
唯有了解病痛的根源
For only when we know what ails us
才有希望找到療法
can we hope to find the cure.
我不會回來了
I will not return.
別再試圖跟我聯絡
Do not attempt to contact me again.
羅蘭潘柏 敬筆
Sincerely, Roland E. Pembroke.
拉克哈先生
Well, Mr. Lockhart...
你怎麼看這封信?
what do you make of that?
他顯然是瘋了
Clearly, he's lost his mind.
跟我們想的一模一樣
Our thoughts exactly.
他去參加兩周水療度假後
Man goes for a two-week spa vacation,
就完全精神崩潰了
and has a complete mental breakdown.
21世紀哪有人還在玩水療這套?
Who the hell takes the waters in the 21 st century anyway?
我想你了解信中有些內客不得外泄
I trust you understand the sensitivity of some of the information in that letter.
所以這是真的
So it's true.
這類並購會讓我們成為
A merger of this kind will make us...
東海岸規模最大的金融服務公司
one of the biggest financial service firms on the Eastern Seaboard.
會議室的每個人都會賺很大
Something that stands to enrich everyone in this room.
包括你在內
Including you.
你的風評不錯
We hear good things.
能處理好雷諾斯的帳戶令人驚討
Your work on the Reynolds account was inspired.
證交委員會肯定會想查公司帳簿
Of course, the SEC will want unfettered access to our books.
不法的地方一定會曝光
Any irregularities are sure to come out.
你該不會以為我們不會發現吧?
You didn't really think we wouldn't find out?
我不曉得你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
你以為你變得出新把戲嗎?
You think there's a trick you can pull we haven't tried?
“年度績效報告”
這手法也太粗糙了
This is amateur.
拉克哈先生 能請教一件事嗎?
Can I ask you something, Mr. Lockhart?
你被30公分的黑屌插過屁眼嗎?
You ever have a 12-inch black dick in your ass?
拉克哈先生 牢獄之災
Prison, Mr. Lockhart.
你麻煩大了
You're in a lot of trouble.
若是這樣 你早就把我交給警方了
If that were the case, you would have already turned me in.
所以我猜證交會要抓的是更高層的人
So, my guess is the SEC is after someone a little more senior.
可能是董事會的一員
Someone on the board, perhaps.
或精神狀況明顯不穩定的人
Or someone who's clearly unstable.
我們要你去瑞士帶潘柏先生回來
We'd like you to go to Switzerland and bring Mr. Pembroke back to us.
是這樣的...
You see...
沒有潘柏簽名 並購案就不能完成
the merger cannot go through without Mr. Pembroke signing off...
有特定法律問題要處理
on certain legal matters.
我跟潘柏光生的關係不如莫里斯
I don't have the relationship with Mr. Pembroke that Morris had.
莫里斯去死
Fuck Morris.
莫里斯是好業務、可靠的顧家男人
Now, Morris was a good salesman, dependable family man.
願他的靈魂安息
God rest his soul.
可是他沒有遠見
But he didn't have vision.
總得有人負起責任
Someone has to take responsibility.
賈許 又是我
Josh, it's me again.
一個半小時後 日經就結束交易了
In an hour and a half, the Nikkei closes.
你到時將拜恩的股票脫手
When it does, I want you to empty Banyon
買下葛蘭柯的賣權
and buy puts in Glenco.
我現在傳細節給你 快回我電話
I'm sending the details over now. And fucking call me back.
我不喜歡留言
I don't like leaving messages like this.
你是來治療的嗎?
You're here for the cure?
不是 我只是探訪
No, I'm just visiting.
你不介意吧?
You mind?
你抽吧
Go ahead.
你比我大部分載的客人年輕
You're younger than most of my passengers.
你常替療養院載客嗎?
Do a lot of driving for the sanitarium?
全部是我載的
All the driving.
我每星期都去車站接有錢人
Every week, I pick up rich people from the train...
載他們上山
and take them up the mountain.
只帶有錢人嗎?
Only rich people, huh?
這裡一定很貴
Must be expensive.
有錢人有富裕的問題
Well, wealthy people have wealthy problems.
我呢 過著簡單的生活就滿足了
Me, I'm happy with a simple life.
就這樣?你都沒有抱負?
That's it? No ambition?
光是載人上下山就滿足了?
Just drive people up and down the mountain?
大部分的人會留下來
Most people tend to stay.
為什麼?
Why's that?
我想他們喜歡療養院
I guess they like it there.
靠
Oh, shit.
“電池量 0%”
我不來水療這一套
I don't go in for spas and that kind of thing.
我工作謀生 就跟我爸一樣
I work for a living, like my father before me.
兒子會向父親學習如何當男人吧?
A son learns what it is to be a man from his father. Am I right?
這我就不知道了
I wouldn't know.
我沒有父親陪伴長大
I didn't grow up with my father.
你要去多久?
How long will you be gone?
幾天而已 洽公
Just a few days. It's business.
你的氣色很差
You don't look well.
我沒事 只是最近睡眠不足
I'm fine. I just haven't been sleeping much.
你需要休息
You need to rest.
我老是告訴你爸要休息...
You know, I always told your father to rest...
但他就是不聽
but he wouldn't listen.
他太沒用了
He was weak.
你又不認識他
You didn't know him.
那是誰的錯?
And whose fault is that?
你在這輕還開心嗎?
So, are you happy here?
院方有好好照顧你嗎?
Are they taking good care of you?
人是來這裡等死的 我哪會開心?
People come here to die. Why would I be happy?
我要升官了
I'm getting a promotion.
我回來就能幫你換個好環境
So, when I get back I'll be able to move you to somewhere better.
靠近海灘什麼
Somewhere near the beach or something.
你不會回來的
You won't come back.
我當然會
Of course I will.
又做新的芭蕾舞伶?
Another ballerina?
她跟別的不一樣
She's not like the others.
怎麼說?
Why's that?
她生活在夢境裡
She lives in a dream.
可是她在跳舞
But she's dancing.
那是因為她不知道自己在作夢
That's because she doesn't know she's dreaming.
好友善的一群人
Friendly bunch.
對啊
Yeah.
村民跟山上的人一向不和
There's always been bad blood between the villagers and the people on the hill.
為什麼
Why's that?
舊恨
History.
這個地方歷史多久了?
How old is this place?
地基可回溯到男爵時代
Foundations date back to the time of the barons.
幾百年來 這塊土地跟這裡的人
For centuries, all this land and everyone in it...
都屬於一個家族
belonged to one family.
范海克莫
The Von Reichmerls.
他們怎麼了?
What happened to them?
故事很曲折
Hmm. Interesting story.
最後一任男爵對血脈純淨著了魔
Apparently, the last baron was so obsessed with the purity of his bloodline...
他決定只有親妹才能替他生子
he decided only his sister was clean enough to carry his child.
教會禁止他們結合後 他棄絕了上帝
When the church forbade the union, he renounced God.
下場一定很慘
That must have gone over well.
那還用說
No shit.
在他的新婚之夜
So on his wedding night...
村民上山
the villagers came up the hill...
追著男爵跟新娘進了地下墓穴
chased the Baron and his bride into the catacombs...
讓他眼睜睜看著她被燒死
and made him watch while they burned her alive.
接著他們放火燒了這裡 夷為平地
Then they burned the whole place to the ground.
好可怕的故事
That's a hell of a story.
對啊
Yeah.
但那是兩百年前的事
But that was 200 years ago.
現在情況不一樣了
A lot's changed since then.
我最多待20分鐘就出來
20 minutes max.
不急
No hurry.
歡迎
Welcome!
請問有什麼事?
May I help you?
我來找一個客人 羅蘭潘柏先生
I'm here to see a guest. Mr. Roland Pembroke.
抱歉 今天的探訪時間已經過了
I'm sorry, but visiting hours are over for the day.
“探訪時間 11至15點”
我長途跋涉
I've come a long way.
可以破個例嗎?
Maybe you could make an exception.
不能破例
There are no exceptions.
我可以找經理談嗎?
Is there a manager I could speak to?
在這裡簽名
Sign here.
麻煩你
Please.
謝謝...拉克哈先生
Thank you, Mr. Lockhart.
我儘量幫你處理
I'll see what I can do.
這裡沒有訊號
You won't get any service here.
這是療程的一部分
Part of the treatment.
久了就習慣了
You get used to it.
特赦10個字母的寫法是啥?
What's a ten-letter word for amnesty?
不曉得
No idea.
免除
Exemption.
不對 那才9個字母
Nope. That's only nine.
赦免
Absolution.
對
Yes!
你喜歡玩字謎嗎?
You like puzzles?
不喜歡
Not really.
麻煩一下好嗎?
You mind?
謝謝
Thank you.
我想櫃檯的護士解釋過了
I believe the reception nurse explained...
探訪時間到3點整結束
that visiting hours end at 3:00 p.m. precisely.
她是說了 但我想你很清楚
She did. But as I'm sure you're aware...
潘柏依舊是某者要金融機構的總栽
Mr. Pembroke remains the CEO of a major financial institution.
在這種情況下 我希望你能開個...
Under the circumstances, I was hoping you can make an...
特例
exception.
維他命
Vitamins.
如果我們要幫助來這療養的人
If we are to help the people that come here...
就得維持體力
we must keep up our strength.
能請教是哪方面的事嗎?
May one ask what it is concerning?
商業機密
It's a business matter.
我無法多說
I'm not at liberty to say any more than that.
沒間題 我希望你能了解
Of course. And I hope you understand
這裡也有自己的規定
that we also have our rules.
我們的療程想發揮最大的效果
Our treatments here are most effective...
就得嚴格限制接觸現代世界的壓力
when exposure to the stresses of the modern world is strictly limited.
沃莫主任對這點頗為堅持
Director Volmer is quite firm on that.
“純淨健康 亨利沃莫”
水療? -是的
Hydrotherapy? That is correct.
就為了水 這路途還真遠
That's a long way to come just for water.
本遼陽院建於古老的含水土層之上
The sanitarium is built over an ancient aquifer...
富有獨特的活化特質
that offers uniquely rejuvenating qualities.
重建
Rebuilt.
在失火以後
After the fire.
是的
Yes.
歷史充滿黑暗面
History is full of darkness.
如果你想留張字條
If you would like to leave a note...
我會轉交給潘柏先生
I'd happily pass it along to Mr. Pembroke.
彼得森先生?
Mr. Pieterson?
我知道你在這裡的工作很重要
I understand the work you do here is important...
你顯然也是大忙人
and you're obviously a very busy man.
但如果你願意在管理水上有氧運動 與按摩浴缸之餘找時間
But if you wouldn't mind finding time between administering aqua aerobics and Jacuzzis...
通知潘柏先生有訪客
to inform Mr. Pembroke he has a visitor...
有緊急要事找他
with information of the utmost urgency to him personally...
我會很感謝
I'd be grateful.
另一方面 如果你要我寫字條
On the other hand, if you want me to write a note...
好隨同早餐托盤塞進門底下
so you can slip it under his door with his breakfast tray...
他在早上按摩前卻不見得能發現
on the off-chance he notices it before his morning rubdown...
那我恐怕不能接受
I'm afraid that's not gonna cut it.
我跑了六千多公里才到了這裡
You see, I just traveled 4,000 miles to get here.
今晚有班紅眼班機回紐約
There's a red-eye going back to New York tonight...
我會帶潘柏先生飛回去
and I intend Mr. Pembroke and I to be on it.
你打算帶潘柏先生跟你回紐約?
You plan to take Mr. Pembroke back to New York with you?
有問題嗎?
Is that a problem?
這當然完全要看潘柏先生的意思
Of course, it is entirely up to Mr. Pembroke.
他是病患 不是囚犯
He's a patient, not a prisoner.
他的療程到7點結束
He'll be in treatment until after 7:00.
你到時候來 我一定讓你見他
If you'd like to come back then, I'll make sure he's available.
謝謝你的諒解
Thank you for your understanding.
你這麼快離開?
Leaving already?
好帥氣的年輕人 -你的朋友呢
What a nice-looking young man.  - Where's your friend?
到蘇黎世最末班火車幾點?
What time's the last train to Zurich?
10點
Not till 10:00.
帶我找間旅館 我得打個電話
Get me to a hotel. I gotta make a call.
正妹
Pretty girl.
搞什麼
What the fuck!
你要去多久?
How long will you be gone?
幾天而已
Just a few days.
你有在等人嗎?
Are we waiting for someone else?
沒有人了
There is no one else.
睡得好嗎?
Sleep well?
我印象中沒睡得這麼甜過 -山上的空氣很新鮮
I can't remember having slept better.  - It's the mountain air.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
我是亨利沃莫 療養院的主任
my name is Henrich Volmer. I am the director of the sanitarium here.
我在這裡待多久了?
How long have I been here?
三天
Three days.
老天
Oh, Jesus!
你的運氣很好 骨折沒粉碎
You can count yourself lucky. It was a clean break.
不過我覺得我有部分的責任
Although I do feel partly responsible.
居民說我應該射殺這裡的鹿
The locals tell me I should hunt the deer on the property...
但我沒辦法傷害這些無辜的動物
but I can't bring myself to harm the innocent creatures.
畢竟·它們早就在這裡了
After all, they were here long before us.
我得打電話到紐約
I need to call New York.
我逕行通知貴公司你出車禍的事了 如果你擔心的是這個
I took the liberty of informing your office of the accident, if that's your concern.
他們跟我的意見一致
They agreed with me...
生意可以等 但你的健康不能等
that business can wait and your health cannot.
漢克葛林親口說的?
Hank Green said that?
就連華爾街大金融公司的代理總栽
Even the acting head of a major Wall Street finance firm...
對嚴重車禍的後果也無法爭辯
can't argue with the consequences of a serious car accident.
這裡的訪客不多
We don't get many visitors here.
多數病患都有過豐功偉業
Most of my patients have done extraordinary things.
創造大筆財富
Built vast fortunes...
管理偉大的企業
commanded great empires...
卻付出慘痛代價
but at a terrible cost.
他們沒有人照顧
They have no one who cares for them.
潘柏先生運氣很好
Mr. Pembroke is lucky.
他還有你
He has you.
所以你儘管休息吧
So, do your best to relax.
開心享受
Enjoy yourself.
這裡是瑞士阿爾卑斯山腳
You are at the foot of the Swiss Alps...
世上最美的仙境之一 -你就當作是強制放假吧
one of the most beautiful places in the world. Think of it as an enforced vacation.
但你們美國人不懂得放假的情趣吧?
Although I know you Americans are not so good at vacations, are you?
別忘了 這是山上
And remember, you're at altitude.
適應可能要一段時間
It can take a while to acclimatize...
所以務必要多喝水
so please make sure you drink plenty of water.
相信我·我們會好好照顧你
Believe me, you're in good hands.
你迷路了嗎?
Are you lost?
對
Uh... Yeah.
我想是
I guess so.
你要去那裡?
Where is it you're supposed to be?
我不知道
I don't know.
你的名字?
Name?
潘柏
Pembroke.
羅蘭潘柏
Roland Pembroke.
找到了
Here it is.
潘柏 609房 蒸汽浴
Pembroke. Room 609. Steam bath.
對喔
Of course.
潘柏先生...
Mr. Pembroke...
蒸汽浴要往那邊走
the steam baths are in that direction.
你不能進去
You can't go in there.
要換衣服才行
Not like that.
潘柏?
Pembroke?
您是潘柏先生吧?
It is Mr. Pembroke, isn't it?
我認識你嗎?
Do I know you?
我是拉克哈 葛林先生派我來的
My name is Lockhart. Mr. Green sent me.
我還以為他們會叫莫里斯來
I thought they'd send Morris.
莫里斯死了
Morris is dead.
心臟病發
Heart attack.
潘柏先生 我是來帶你回紐約的
Mr. Pembroke, I've come to bring you back to New York.
你要我離開這裡?
You want me to leave here?
幾天就好
Just for a few days.
我恐怕辦不到
I'm afraid I can't do that.
為什麼不行?
Why not?
我生病了
I'm not well.
你看起來好好的啊
You look all right to me.
那是因為你視而不見
That's because you are blind.
我從前也這樣
As I was.
但你很快就會明白了
But soon you'll see.
放心吧 這裡的人會好好照顧你
Rest assured, they'll take good care of you here.
我不是病人
I'm not a patient.
你的腿怎麼了?
What happened to your leg?
潘柏先生 紐約的情勢很嚴峻
Mr. Pembroke, the situation in New York is really quite serious.
已經跟我與關了
No longer my concern.
主任要我別掛念事業
The director says I must not involve myself in business matters.
你見過沃莫主任了嗎?
Have you met Director Volmer?
今天早上見了
This morning.
他是很好的人
He is a great man.
心地善良 跟其他醫生不一樣
Kind man. Not like other doctors.
潘柏先生
Mr. Pembroke...
大家對血液走火入魔
This obsession with blood.
他們全搞錯了
You see, they have it all wrong.
你知道身體有65％是水嗎?
Do you know the body is 65% water?
我們的體液必須淨化
It's our fluids that must be purified.
並購有問題的消息走漏了
Word that the merger is in trouble has leaked.
股價因此暴跌 拉克哈?
The share price is in free fall. Lockhart?
你該不會跟亨利拉克哈有關係吧?
You're not any relation to Henry Lockhart, are you?
他是我爸
My father.
你認識他?
You knew him?
我們在同時期創業
We started out together.
他的下場可真凄慘
Terrible, what happened to him.
聽說有個男孩被留在車上
They said there was a boy left in the car.
說真的 我不太記得了
I don't remember much, to be honest.
他不應該受到我們那樣的對待
He didn't deserve what we did to him.
什麼意思? -他是正直的人
What do you mean? He was an honest man.
我們卻把他害慘了
And we destroyed him for it.
每天都有人被弄
Well, people get fucked over every day.
就看你有沒有生存的本事
Either you have what it takes to survive, or you don't.
那我想你有咯
And I suppose you do.
這是你大老遠跑來的原因?
Is that why you came all this way?
為了抱負?
Ambition?
那你就比我們都還要嚴重
Then you have it worse than any of us.
什麼東西?
What's that?
病啊
The sickness.
你爸早在我們之前就看清真相
Your father saw the truth long before the rest of us.
這些努力毫無意義
The pointlessness of the entire endeavor.
大家都做過可怕的事
We've all done terrible things.
可怕的事做太多了
So many terrible things.
交易金額是多少?
What's it trading at?
什麼?
What?
股票的交易金額是多少
The stock! What's it trading at?
星期五收盤時每股8.5塊 -寄生蟲
Eight and a half at close on Friday. Parasites.
現在價格會更低
It'll be lower by now.
潘柏先生 大家都很關心你的健康
We're all concerned for your well-being, Mr. Pembroke.
幾天就好
Just a few days.
部分帳戶出現異常
There are certain irregularities in some of the accounts...
釐清後才能完成並購
that need to be clarified before the merger can be completed.
我想總得有人負起責任
And I suppose someone has to take responsibility.
之類的
Something like that.
那我最好去收拾東西
Then I better get my things.
我需要一輛車載我去車站
I need a car to take me to the station.
你能幫我叫車嗎? -我會儘量幫你處理
Will you call one for me, please? I'll see what I can do.
這是男爵吊死神父的地方
That's where the baron hung the priest.
什麼?-你看
- What's that? - See?
教堂原本在那裡
The church would have been right over there...
現在被這怪建築取代了 我確定
where that funny little building is now. I'm sure of it.
從前的人會遠道而來
People used to come from miles around...
求聖水的神奇功效
for the miracles attributed to the holy water.
我想有些事情是不會變的
Guess some things don't change.
真是了不起
How marvelous.
不過這種暴力實在可怕
Terrible thing, though. Such violence.
娶妹妹就會這樣
That's what you get for marrying your sister.
妹妹? -對 一切都為了血統純淨吧?
Sister? Yeah, it was all about a pure bloodline, wasn't it?
好精彩
How fascinating!
我一定要查一查
I must look into that.
很高興你能走路了
Glad to see you're back on your feet!
我們聽說車禍的事了
We heard about the accident.
你是美國人吧?先生貴姓 -拉克哈
You're American, aren't you, Mister... Lockhart.
法蘭克希爾 斯德哥爾摩人
Frank Hill. Stockholm.
這是倫敦來的奈爾先生
And this is Mr. Nair from London.
我原本住在孟買
Bombay, originally.
你見到業餘歷史學者瓦金斯太太了 -沒錯 我真沒禮貌
I see you've met Mrs. Watkins, our amateur historian. Yes, of course. How rude.
維多莉亞瓦金斯 我在全錄待了40年 -你拉張椅子坐吧?
Victoria Watkins. 40 years at Xerox. Why don't you pull up a chair?
我們三缺一
We need a fourth.
小心 他像波羅門的人一樣會作弊
Careful. Like most Brahmins, he cheats.
從創投家的口中說出這句話
Coming from a venture capitalist,
我當是恭維
I take that as a compliment.
其實 我準備跟潘柏先生一起回紐約
Actually, I was just on my way back to New York with Mr. Pembroke.
那麼他...
Then he's...
他的身體好點了?
He's feeling better?
夠好了
Well enough.
我想這是好消息
I suppose that's wonderful news.
奈爾先生 可不是嗎?
Isn't that right, Mr. Nair?
很好的消息
Wonderful news.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins...
你該做療程了
time for your treatment.
沒問題
Yes, of course.
拉克哈先生 很高興認識你
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Lockhart.
一路平安
Safe travels.
水裡有東西嗎?
Something in the water?
在水底
At the bottom.
我什麼都看不到
I don't see anything.
會痛嗎?
Did it hurt?
我不記得了
Can't remember.
這樣反而好
Better that way.
我有看到你
I saw you.
之前看到過
Before.
你是這裡的病人嗎?
Are you a patient here?
你比其他人都年輕很多
It's just, you're so much younger than everyone else.
沃莫主任說我是特殊案例
Director Volmer says I'm a special case.
那你呢?
What about you?
你是來接受治療的嗎?
Are you here for the cure?
不是
No.
其實我正要離開
Actually, I was just leaving.
沒人離開過這裡
No one ever leaves.
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
為什麼有人會想要離開?
Why would anyone want to?
我懂你的意思
Yeah, I see your point.
你來的目的達到了嗎?
Did you get what you came for?
我來帶一個人回紐約
Well, I came to bring someone back to New York.
所以我的目的達到了
So, yeah. I did.
他想走嗎?
Does he want to go?
不太想
Not really.
你剛剛哼唱那首歌
That song you were singing.
是在哪裡學的?
Where did you learn that?
我得走了
I have to go now.
你叫什麼名字?
What's your name?
漢娜
Hannah.
“今細探訪時間已過”
潘柏先生?
Mr. Pembroke?
潘柏呢?
Where's Pembroke?
原本在這間病房的人去哪了?
The patient that was in this room, where is he?
我還以為你是潘柏
I thought you were Pembroke.
大家知道從前胃痛的建議療法嗎?
Do you know what they used to recommend for the common stomach ailment?
使用水蛭
The application of leeches.
根據診斷 我一向同情水蛭
Based on the diagnosis, I always pitied the leech.
拉克哈先生...
Mmm. Mr. Lockhart...
請加入我們吧
please, won't you join us?
鱘魚很好吃 你愛鹿肉也行
The sturgeon is excellent, unless of course you prefer the venison.
我不能浪費那頭鹿
I couldn't let it go to waste.
潘柏呢?
Where's Pembroke?
很不幸 潘柏先生病情加重了
Mr. Pembroke has unfortunately taken a turn for the worse.
恐怕你們談生意的事
I fear your conversation about business matters...
讓他的情況惡化了
has set him back somewhat.
但不重要
But, no matter. We have moved him on
我們送他去做下一階段的療程了
to the next stage of treatment.
我覺得他看來好好的
He looked all right to me.
但你不是醫生
But you're not a doctor.
說不定該徵求第二意見了
Maybe it's time for a second opinion.
要走要留就看潘柏先生的意思
That, of course, is up to Mr. Pembroke.
但他不能見客
And he's not available.
自從我來了以後
Ever since I got here...
你們就一跟我兜圈子
you people have been giving me the runaround.
請你降低音量
I would ask you please to keep your voice down.
我們可不想讓客戶不開心吧
We wouldn't wanna upset the clientele, would we?
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart, giving you the runaround
我並沒有跟你兜圈子
is the furthest thing from my mind.
我只關心我病患的福利
My sole concern is for the welfare of my patients.
病人開始好轉就會影響你們的生意
It's bad for business if people start getting better.
我說得對嗎?
Am I right?
拉克哈先生 你的言下之意是什麼?
What are you implying, Mr. Lockhart?
老人花大錢做什麼?喝水?
Old people paying through the teeth for what? Water?
你的開銷到底是多少?
What's your overhead anyway?
那不關你的事
That is not your concern.
我不想把律師牽扯進來
I don't wanna have to get lawyers involved...
但我是來帶潘柏回紐約的
but I came to get Pembroke back to New York...
我要把人帶走 就算我得敲破他的頭
and that's what I'm gonna do, if I have to hit him over his head...
揪著頭髮把他抱出去也在所不辭
and drag him out by his hair.
拉克哈先生 你還好嗎?你的臉色很蒼白
Are you feeling all right, Mr. Lockhart? You seem pale.
我沒事
I'm fine.
你流血了
You're bleeding.
什麼?
What?
你還是坐下來吧
Perhaps you should sit down.
沒有腦震盪跡拿
No signs of concussion.
你會頭痛、出現幻覺嗎?
Any headaches, hallucinations?
沒有
No.
你可以穿衣服了
You may dress.
你有在喝水嗎?
Are you drinking the water?
有
Yes.
很好
Good.
一定要喝水
Make sure you do.
我在車禍後擅自替你做了幾項檢查
I took the liberty of running a few tests after the accident.
漢娜
Hannah.
這是她吧?
Isn't it?
對
Yes.
她是特殊案例
She's a very special case.
什麼意思?
What does that mean exactly?
她小時候遭遇嚴重的創傷
She was exposed to serious trauma when she was very young.
她的發育遲緩
Her development was delayed.
直到11歲才開口說話
Hannah did not utter a word until she was 11 years old.
請你要了解
Please understand...
拉克哈先生...
Mr. Lockhart...
她對我來說 情同女兒
she is like a daughter to me.
但我們要討論的是你的事
But we're here to discuss you.
你的體液不平衡
An imbalance in your fluids.
重大器官損傷
Strain to the major organs.
免疫系統耗竭
Depleted immune system.
許多跡象指出你跟多數病患一樣
Many indicators that you have in common with most of my patients...
但我坦承從來沒看過
but I will confess I have never seen a case...
這麼嚴重的病情
as advanced as this...
發生在這麼年輕的人身上
in someone so young.
是嗎?
Is that right?
拉克哈先生 告訴我
Tell me, Mr. Lockhart...
你最後一次覺得身強體壯是何時?
when was the last time that you actually felt well?
在你來之前
Before you came here, when was the last time...
你最後一次一覺到天亮是何時?
that you even slept through the night?
心理可能會說謊
The mind may lie...
但身體可騙不了人
but the body cannot.
我想幫助你
I should like to help you.
本院提供的是
What we offer here...
簡單的淨化過程
is a simple process of purification.
遠離現代世界的壓力
Away from pressures of the modern world.
回歸單純的年代
A return to a simpler time.
潘柏先生一兩天內不能出遠門
Mr. Pembroke will not be ready to travel for a day or two.
你願意的話
And if you're willing...
我想推薦一個療程
I would like to recommend a treatment.
我能跟當班的護士說
I can speak to the duty nurse...
今天晚上就能開始進行
and we may be able to start as early as this evening.
你覺得有必要就做吧
If you think it's necessary.
很好
Good.
葛瑞塔
Greta?
葛瑞塔?
“羅蘭潘柏”
拉克哈先生 你的運氣真好
You're in luck, Mr. Lockhart.
我們能馬上幫你安排
We can get you in right away.
“VR”
"VR."
范海克莫的意思
Von Reichmerl.
這是重建時發現的
It was found during the reconstruction.
那這就是男爵的墜子咯?
Then it belong to the baron?
其實是男爵夫人的
The baroness, actually.
凡妮莎范海克莫
Vanessa Von Reichmerl.
她體弱多病
She was sickly.
男爵執意要找到療法
The Baron was obsessed with finding a cure.
事實上 他是第一個
It was he, in fact, who first discovered
發現這裡的水有療效
the medicinal properties of our water.
他無所不用其極
He sacrificed everything.
他一定很愛她
He must have loved her very much.
是的
Yes.
當妹妹一樣愛
Like a sister.
歷史以道德角度批判他當然是對的
History is right, of course, to judge him on moral grounds.
但身為科學之人
But, as a man of science...
我對他只有欣賞
I can't help but admire him.
當班護士會帶你去隔離區
The duty nurse will escort you to our isolation wing.
謝謝
Thank you.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
希望你不會介意
If you wouldn't mind.
這樣我們才能監控你的進展
Just so we can keep an eye on your progress.
“維多莉亞瓦金斯”
拉克哈先生 您準備好了嗎?
Are you ready, Mr. Lockhart?
那我們開始吧
Then let us begin.
地球的生物首先從水中出現
Life on this planet first came from water.
我們頭九個月沉浸在液體中
We spend the first nine months of our existence submerged...
身體多數為液體所組成
our bodies mostly liquid.
感官去除室能模擬
This sensory deprivation chamber simulates a return...
讓人回歸胚胎狀態
to that embryonic state.
就當成是淨化心靈...
Think of it as a cleansing of the mind...
與淨化身體吧
as much as the body.
有些病患會心跳加速
Some patients experience increased heart rate...
出現幻覺
visions...
甚至出現早期記憶
even primal memories.
但請放...這只是毒素排出體外
But rest assured, it's just the toxins leaving the system.
完全投入這個過程
Give yourself over completely to the process...
你就會看到成果
and you will see the results.
注意看好他
Keep a close eye on him.
好的
Yes, sir.
拉克哈先生 療程總共30分鐘
Mr. Lockhart... the treatment lasts 30 minutes.
我會從這裡監控 有任何問題
I'll be monitoring you from here. If you have any issues...
此敲水槽
just tap on the side of the tank.
退後
Get back!
過去五天 股市完全崩盤
In the last five days, a total collapse.
道瓊指數狂跌超過508點
The Dow plunging over 508 points...
華爾街彌漫著恐慌
as panic spread throughout Wall Street...
有超過三分之一的獲利
wiping out more than one-third of the gains...
從這罕見的五年牛市蒸發
from this rare, five-year bull market.
其中超過一半發生於單一交易日
More than half of that in a single trading day.
紐約證交所主席約翰菲蘭
Chairman of New York Stock Exchange, John Phelan...
試圖安定投資人信心
tried to reassure investors.
爸
Dad?
Dad!
拉克哈先生 你沒事吧?
Mr. Lockhart, are you all right?
放開我
Get off me.
別激動
Try to stay calm.
很抱歉 儀器一定出了問題
I'm terribly sorry. Something must have gone wrong with the machine.
水裡有東西
There's something in the water.
水裡他媽的有東西
There's something in the fucking water.
拉克哈先生 水裡沒東西
There is nothing in the water, Mr. Lockhart.
可是我看到了
But I saw them.
主任解釋過了
As the Director explained...
這套療程會使某些病患出現幻覺
some patients experience visions with this particular treatment.
這只是毒素排出體外
Just the toxins leaving the body.
是療程的一部分
It's all part of the cure.
你得休息了
You need to rest now.
我扶你回去房間
I will help you to your room.
逮到你了
Got you.
拉克哈 早
Morning, Lockhart.
你好點了嗎?
Feeling better?
要一起吃早餐嗎?
Joining us for breakfast?
鱈魚咖哩飯很香
The kedgeree is excellent.
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
你可得好好保持體力
You must keep up your strength.
瓦金斯太太?
Mrs. Watkins?
教堂的原址...
That building where the church used to be...
現在的用途是什麼?
What's it used for now?
我也不曉得
I couldn't say.
男爵跟他妹妹的事你說對了
You were right about the baron and his sister.
但那不是村民燒了這裡的源因
But that's not the reason the villagers burned the place down.
而是實驗的關係
It was on account of the experiments.
某種醫學實驗
Some sort of medical experiments.
“男爵夫人 范海克莫 凡妮莎 實臉”
“屍體 妹妹 神父 婚禮 大火”
他用自己的人民當白老鼠
Apparently performed on his own peasants.
有些人失蹤了
People went missing.
後來
And then...
在1814年...
Im Jahre 1814...
農夫在耕田時發現死人
farmers, tilling their fields, stumbled on human bodies...
遭到破壞且皮包骨
disfigured and emaciated.
就像埃及木乃伊一樣
Dried up like the mummies of Egypt.
他在找療法
He was looking for a cure.
療法? -為了治療男爵夫人
- A cure? - For the baroness.
她病了
She was sick.
我了解了
Oh, I see.
“療法”
我就知道你喜歡字謎
I knew you liked puzzles.
果然沒錯
Of course.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins...
你該做療程了
time for your treatment.
你確定嗎?
Are you certain?
我早上才做過一次 我確定
I just had one this morning. I'm sure of it.
時間表上有你
I have you on the schedule.
我今天一定是有問題
I must not be feeling myself today.
這裡黑暗又邪惡
There is a terrible darkness here.
這是什麼地方?
What is this place?
抱歉 我不懂
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
我看到你跟一個病人在一起
I thought I saw you with a patient.
不是 病人
No. Patient.
好
Okay.
謝謝
Thank you.
你要去游泳嗎?
Going for a swim?
我不能游
I'm not supposed to.
怎麼說?
Why's that?
因為我生病了
On the account of my condition.
我還以為水會讓病情好轉
Thought the water made you better.
跟你說過了 我是特殊案例
Told you. I'm a special case.
對
Right.
從這裡到鎮上有多遠?
How far is it to town?
我想有幾公里吧
A few miles, I think.
你要一路走過去嗎?
Are you going to walk all the way?
除非你想借我腳踏車
Unless you wanna lend me your bike.
你要拿什麼來謝我?
What will you give me?
這原本是我媽的
It was my mother's.
她的眼睛閉著
Her eyes are closed.
對 她在作夢·只是她不知道
Yeah, she's dreaming. She just doesn't know it.
她醒過來會怎樣?
What happens if she wakes up?
我不知道
I don't know.
我媽一在沒有說到結局
My mother never finished the story.
所以我們說定了嗎?
So, we got a deal?
你要怎麼騎車?
How will you ride it?
你可以一起來啊
Maybe you could come along.
我不能出去
I'm not supposed to.
你一向這麼聽話嗎?
You always do what you're supposed to do?
沒關係
It's okay.
要來嗎?
Coming?
你要喝啤酒嗎?
Want a beer or something?
我不知道 我要嗎?
I don't know. Do I?
我不知道你想要什麼
I don't know what you want.
好 你喝我就喝
All right. If you're having one.
你還在這裡?
Still here?
我以為你只走訪客
Thought you were just visiting.
你看起來好多了
You've looked better.
你也是
Same to you.
你的車子還好嗎?
How's the car?
我的車全毀了
That car was a piece of shit.
療養院賠的錢夠我買一輛新車
Sanitarium offered me enough to buy a new one.
所以 謝天謝地
So, gracias a Dios.
事出必有因 對嗎?
Everything happens for a reason, right?
你喝太多了
You drink too much.
你可別開車
I hope you're not driving.
你們兩個是從山上來的?
You two are from up on the hill?
對
That's right.
這裡不常有病人下來
We don't get many patients down here.
這些小孩心地善良
Good kids at heart.
只是沒教好
Just weren't raised properly.
不尊重傳統
No respect for tradition.
你知道鎮上有醫生嗎?
Know if there's a doctor in town?
醫生全都在山上了
All the doctors are up on the hill.
有藥師嗎?
A pharmacist?
之類的人?
Something like that?
可以找彼特 繞過去就到了
There's Pieter. Over the road.
他是醫生嗎?
He a doctor?
夠接近了
Close enough.
你不喜歡?
Don't you like it?
不喜歡
No.
怎麼 這輩子沒喝過啤酒?
What, you never had a beer before?
你待在療養院多久了?
How long have you been at the sanitarium?
從我有記憶以來
Since I can remember.
那你的家人呢?
What about your family?
我媽在我小時候被火燒死了
My mother died in a fire when I was young.
沃莫主任說等我好一點
Director Volmer says that my father will come for me
我爸就會來接我
when I'm better.
他會來看你嗎?
Does he visit?
等我好一點他就會來
He'll come when I'm better.
維他命? -對
- Vitamins? - Mmm-hmm.
我可以試試嗎?
Can I try?
好
Okay.
味道像臭海鮮
Tastes like sweaty seafood.
你最後會習慣的
You get used to it. Eventually.
你在這裡待一下沒關係吧?
Will you be okay here for a few minutes?
我得去處理一件事 不會太久
I just have to go see about something. But I won't be long.
好啊
Uh... Yeah. Okay.
哈囉
Hello?
你知道這裡有醫生嗎?
Do you know if there's a doctor here?
你畫的是什麼?
What's that you're drawing?
他不會跟你說話的
He won't talk to you.
他不會說話
Doesn't know how.
那是城堡...
That's the castle...
失火的時候
when they burned it down.
這是我孫子威莫許
My grandson, Wilmosh.
他喜歡鬼故事
He likes ghost stories.
你有什麼事?
What can I do for you?
你可以幫我看一下 這份病歷上面寫什麼嗎?
Could you take a look at this, tell me what it says?
這是人的嗎?
Human?
對
That's right.
不是我的專業
Not my line.
我願意付你錢
I'll pay you.
這樣是多少錢?
How much is this?
沒多少
Not much.
但是夠了
But enough.
你有棉條嗎?
Got a tampon?
我朋友的大姨媽來了
My friend's time of the month.
怪胎
Freak.
所以他能出遠門嗎?
So is he fit to travel?
他生病了
He's not a well man.
有些是牙科的病歷吧?
Some of those are dental records, aren't they?
對 -那是什麼意思?
- That's right. - What do they mean?
他在掉牙齒
His teeth are falling out.
可能的病因是什麼?
What could cause something like that?
撇開先前的病不說 我認為是...
Barring any pre-existing condition, I'd say...
慢性脫水
chronic dehydration.
脫水?
Dehydration?
山上的人都只會喝水而已啊
All they do up there is drink water.
我不是醫生
I'm not a doctor.
抱歉 我還有事...
Now, if you'll excuse me...
等一下
Wait a second.
男爵的實臉
The baron's experiments.
有人在田裡發現屍體 對嗎?
They found bodies in the fields, right?
跟木乃伊一樣
Dried up like mummies.
說不定事情有關聯
Maybe there's some kind of connection.
兩百年前 男爵在新婚之夜 就被活活燒死了
The baron was burned alive on his wedding night 200 years ago.
對 但這是現在的事
Yeah, but this is happening now.
人們會來這裡治療
People come here for the cure.
男爵就是要找療法 他的夫人病了
That's what the baron was looking for. His wife was sick.
她沒生病
She wasn't sick.
她是不能生育
She was infertile.
他們努力了很多年
They tried for years.
但男爵夫人都半途流產
But the baroness could not carry a child to term.
大家說她的身體
They say her body rejected the fetuses
因為胎兒畸形產生排斥
because they were deformed.
抱歉 我真的有事
Now, you must excuse me.
我得了結這頭牛的痛苦
I have to put this animal out of its misery.
它怎慶了?
What's wrong with it?
他溜達去不該去的地方
Wandered off where it wasn't supposed to be.
摔斷了腿
Broke its leg.
就像你一樣
Like you.
我發現它困在排水溝
Found it trapped in a drainage ditch...
喝臭溝水
drinking sewage water.
我得打一通長途電話
I need to make a phone call. Long distance.
信用卡拿來
Your credit card.
拉克哈
Lockhart.
葛林先生
Mr. Green.
你到底去哪了?
Where the hell have you been?
我有一個問題
I have a question.
潘柏有任何舊疾嗎?
Did Pembroke have any pre-existing conditions?
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
他來之前有生什麼病嗎?
Before he got here. Any medical conditions? Was he sick?
沒有 他是保健狂
No. The guy is a fucking health nut.
會喝甘藍汁那種神經病
Drank kale for Christ's sake.
到底是怎麼回事?
Now what the fuck is going on?
你四天前就該回來的
You were supposed to be here four days ago.
對 可是後來我出意外了
Yeah. But there was an accident.
什麼意外?
What accident?
什麼?
What?
我不懂 他們說有打電話給你
I don't understand. They said they called you.
沒人打給我
Nobody called.
你確定嗎?
Are you sure about that?
拉克哈 我得跟你重申
Lockhart, do I have to reiterate to you...
你出這趟差的重要性嗎?
the importance of what you've been sent there to do?
24小時內帶潘柏上飛機
Get Pembroke on a plane within the next 24 hours...
否則這裡就天下大亂了
or this whole place goes ass over tits.
連你也一樣遭殃 懂嗎?
And you with it. Understand me?
拉克哈?
Lockhart?
拉克哈
Lockhart!
我有話跟你說 -喂...
- I need to speak with you - Hey, hey, hey.
你說沒人會離開這裡是啥意思?
You said no one ever leaves. What does that mean?
你弄痛我了
You're hurting me.
他們會怎樣? -拜託放開我
- What happens to them? - Please let me go.
院方為什麼不讓我見潘柏?
Why won't they let me see Pembroke?
你知道內幕 對不對? -不知道
You know something, don't you? No.
這是什麼?你為什麼是特殊案例?
What is this stuff? What makes you special?
阿道失 滾開
Fuck off, Adolf!
嘿
Hey!
快點 -不
- Come on. - No!
我付了錢跳這支舞 -不
- I paid for this dance. - No!
放開她
Let her go!
跋腳的滾回療養院吧
Go back to the sanitarium, cripple.
不
No!
不 拜託住手
No! Please, stop!
我不是病人
I am not a patient.
漢娜
Hannah.
她或許有女人的外表
She may look like a woman...
但她的內心只是個孩子
but she's just a child.
拉克哈先生 無知...
Ignorance, Mr. Lockhart...
是科學的大敵
is the great enemy of science.
我要見潘柏
I wanna see Pembroke.
你會見到的
And you will.
拉克哈先生 你來不來?
Coming, Mr. Lockhart?
什麼事也沒發生
Nothing happened.
那是因為我及時趕到
That's because I arrived when I did.
有拉克哈在
Lockhart was there.
他都被刀架住脖子了
With a knife to his throat.
漢娜...
Hannah...
拉克哈連自己都照顧不了
Mr. Lockhart is not able to look after himself,
更何況是照顧你
let alone you.
他不像我可以保護你
He can't protect you the way I can.
我不需要保護 -你當然需要
I don't need protecting. Of course you do.
我們只是出去玩
We were just having fun.
他跟別人不一樣
He's not like the others.
他很年輕
He's young.
幹嘛?
What?
怎麼了? -沒事
- What is it? - Nothing.
讓我看 -不要
- Let me see. - No.
我是你的醫生 過來
I'm your doctor. Come here.
不要 別碰我
No! Don't touch me!
我什麼時候會做好準備?
When will I be ready?
就快了
Soon.
什麼時候?
When?
要有耐心
Patience.
過來
Come here.
我叫你過來
I said, come here.
一直都是我照顧你的吧?
Now, haven't I always looked after you?
你很快就會好轉
Soon, I will make you better.
也會感謝我的
And you will thank me.
然後我爸就會來了?
And my father will come?
對
Yes.
小寶貝 休息吧
Get some rest, my little lamb.
有事嗎?
Bitte?
我出問題了...
I have a problem with my...
可以給我嗎?
May I?
我把它放進牛奶裡吧
I'll just pop it in some milk, shall I?
“潘柏 輸液區”
好了
There we are.
瓦金斯太太
Mrs. Watkins?
潘柏呢?
Where's Pembroke?
你帶他走了
You took him.
回紐約去了
Back to New York.
什麼?沒有
What? No.
院方把他移走了 他在下面這區
They moved him. He's down here somewhere.
記得你跟我說過實驗的事嗎?
You told me about the experiments, remember?
你的字謎?
Your puzzle?
我喜歡字謎
I like puzzles.
對
Yeah.
我留給你了
I left it for you.
你會明白的
You'll see.
聽我說
Listen to me.
實驗...
The experiments...
我覺得又開始了
I think they're happening again.
男爵夫人無法生育
The baroness was infertile.
不是實驗
Not experiments.
是療法
A cure.
她在新婚之夜就懷孕了
She was pregnant the night of the wedding.
村民燒死她之前
Before they burned her...
把胎兒挖出來
the villagers cut out the fetus...
扔進含水土層裡
and threw it in the aquifer.
那孩子沒死
The child survived.
她不曉得
She doesn't know.
抱歉 我不懂
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
別激動
Take it easy.
馬可斯
Marcus!
沒事
It's all right.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart...
不管我走到哪裡
every time I turn around,
你總是在不該去的地方
you're somewhere you're not supposed to be.
我想我迷路了
I guess I'm lost.
我只是在找路回房間
I'm just trying to find my way back to my room.
這個樓層禁止進入 到處都有標示
This is a restricted floor. There are signs everywhere.
你不是不小心撞進來的吧?
Surely you didn't just wander down here by accident?
你到底在找什麼?
What is it exactly that you are looking for?
我的牙齒有問題
I had a problem with my tooth.
你的牙齒?
Your tooth?
其實 我感覺好多了
Actually, it's feeling much better.
麻煩你告訴我怎麼回房間
If you could just point me in the direction of my room.
別胡說
Nonsense.
我們可不能讓你感染了
We can't let you get an infection.
你一定要讓我們照顧你
You must let us take care of you.
畢竟...
After all...
這是你來療養院的原因
that's why you're here.
病人的牙齒健康都由布南醫生負責
Doctor Brennan takes care of all our patients' dental needs.
對不起
I'm sorry.
漢娜的事是我不對
Hmm? About Hannah.
不會有下次了
It won't happen again.
告訴我...
Tell me...
你去鎮上做什麼?
what were you doing in town?
只是喝啤酒
Just having a beer.
你們要幹嘛?
What are you doing?
放開我
Get your hands off me!
拉克哈先生 這是為了你的安全著想
It's all for your own safety, Mr. Lockhart.
本院不相信化學麻醉
We don't believe in chemical anesthesia at the institute.
它的雜質會抑制療效
The impurities inhibit the cure.
但你會發現只要焦點對了
But, you will find that with a proper focus...
心理就能克服所有的痛苦
the mind can overcome any amount of pain.
拉克哈先生 懷抱信任吧
Trust, Mr. Lockhart. Hmm?
如果我們不能彼此信任
I mean, if we can't trust each other...
我又怎麼幫得了你呢?
then how can I help you?
阿伯莫太太...
Mrs. Abramov...
很高興你來了
so glad that you are here.
你要在這裡待多久?
How long do we have you with us?
就兩個星期
Just two weeks.
我可能帶太多行李了
I probably overpacked.
沒有的事
Nonsense.
在本院時間之飛快會讓你驚訝的
You'll be surprised how time just slips away here at the institute.
快開車
Drive!
你的臉怎麼了? -開車就對了
What happened to your face? Just drive!
他們壓住我 硬拔表的牙齒
They held me down and pulled my tooth out.
他們威脅我
They threatened me.
他們為什麼要這麼做?
Why would they do that?
因為我知道他們的勾當
Because I know what they've done.
有個房間全部都是屍體 像標本一樣在水缸裡漂浮
There is a room full of bodies floating in tanks like specimens.
這可是非常嚴重的指控
These are very serious allegations.
沒錯
No shit.
沃莫醫師受人尊敬
Director Volmer is a well-respected man.
療養院對地方經濟舉足輕重
The sanatorium is of great importance for the local economy.
載我上去 我帶你去看
Take me up there, and I'll show you what I saw.
你身上有帶證件嗎?
Do you have any identification on you?
沒有 都被他捫扣走了
No, they have everything.
那麼我可以跟誰談話
Well, then, is there someone I could speak to...
證實你的身分?你有家人嗎?
who might confirm you are who you say you are? Family?
希望你能諒解查證你身分的必要性
I hope you understand the need to verify your identity.
你可以打到我的辦公室
You can call my office.
好
All right.
你要喝咖啡或茶嗎?
Can I get you coffee or tea?
你有酒嗎?
You got anything stronger?
當然有
Of course.
放心吧
Rest assured...
我們會查個水落石出
we will get to the bottom of this.
謝謝
Thank you.
拉克哈先生 我們一直在擔心你
Mr. Lockhart, we've been worried about you.
不要過來
Stay away from me!
他是你們的病人嗎?
Is this man a patient of yours?
沒錯
Yes, that's right.
我不是病人·我是出了意外
I'm not a patient. I was in an accident.
你簽了住院表了 我有帶來
You signed the admission form. I have it right here.
狗屁
That's bullshit.
記得我警告過你可能會出現幻覺吧
I did warn you about possible delusions, remember?
那是毒素排出體外的副作用
A side effect of the toxins leaving the body.
那我的腿是幻覺嗎?
And my leg, is that a delusion?
拉克哈先生自從來了以後 就一直搞破壞
Mr. Lockhart has been a disruptive element since he arrived.
他偷走不對外公開的病歷
He stole confidential medical files...
攻擊一名牙科人員
assaulted a member of our Dental staff...
還威脅潘柏先生
and threatened Mr. Pembroke.
我沒有威脅任何人
I didn't threaten anybody!
我想你的確切字句是
I believe your exact words were...
就算敲破他的頭
"If I have to, I'll hit him over the head
揪著頭髮把他拖出去也在所不辭
"and drag him out by his hair."
我被派來就是要帶潘柏回鈕約
I was sent here to bring Pembroke back to New York!
根據你的雇主葛林先生的說詞
According to your employer, a Mr. Green...
你遭到證交委員會調查
you're being investigated by the Securities and Exchange Commission.
你是他們的人
You're one of them.
拉克哈先生 聽聽你自己說的話
Listen to yourself, Mr. Lockhart.
你生病了
You're not a well man.
別再說我病了
Stop saying that!
讓我們幫你吧 -別過來
- Let us help you. - Get back!
我知道實驗的事
I know about the experiments.
男爵跟他夫人的事
The baron and his wife.
他太常跟瓦金斯太太說話了
He has been spending time with Mrs. Watkins.
瓦金斯是誰?
Who is Watkins?
她在來我們這之前住過精神病院
She was institutionalized before she came to us.
別人都會順著她
The others humor her...
很顯然的 拉克哈因為生病
but clearly Mr. Lockhart's condition
被她的除謀論影響了
has made him susceptible to her conspiracies.
我知道你們在玩什麼把戲
I know what you're trying to do. All of you.
想讓我以為我瘋了
You're trying to make me think I'm insane.
我看過這種情況
I have seen this before.
這很常見
It's not uncommon.
深植內心的童年創傷浮出檯面
Some deep-seated childhood trauma rises to the surface...
病患逃避一輩子就會這樣
something a patient has been running from their entire life.
就你的情況來說
In your case...
我認為你因為你父親的死
I would say misplaced guilt...
而怪罪自已
over the death of your father.
你怎麼會知道這件事? 我從來沒跟你說過
How do you know about that? I never told you that.
你不用多說
You didn't have to.
這是你來本院的原因吧?
That's why you came to us, isn't it?
我看到他了
I saw him.
潘柏死了
Pembroke is dead.
鬧成這樣就是為了這件事?
That's what this is all about?
邪惡的醫生殺死病人?
The evil doctor killing off his patients?
沒錯
That's right.
好 那我們就請教潘柏先生吧
All right. Perhaps we should consult Mr. Pembroke.
你認識這個人嗎
Do you know this man?
他想把我強押回去
He tried to take me back against my will.
潘柏先生
Pembroke?
拜託別讓他靠近我
Please keep him away from me.
你死了
You were dead.
你想提告嗎?
Do you wish press charges?
沒有必要
That won't be necessary.
拉克哈先生不是壞人
Mr. Lockhart is not a criminal.
他只是病了
He is a patient.
致董事會
To the members of the board...
各位派我來此有所目的
You sent me here for a purpose.
那就是強押一個人
To retrieve a man against his will...
帶回你們的世界
and bring him back to your world.
但我現在明白了
But I realize now...
那不是我來的原因
that is not the reason I am here.
每個人的內在都有某種病態
There is a sickness inside each of us.
我們竭盡所能否認它的存在
We do our best to deny its existence...
用逃避
dealing in lies...
或是謊言來面對
and distraction.
直到有一天
Until one day the body rebels against the mind
身體對心理反抗吶喊
and screams out...
我生病了
"I am not a well man."
人無法忽視真相
A man cannot unsee the truth.
一旦看見光明
He cannot willingly return to darkness...
就不可能自願回歸黑晴或選擇失明
or go blind once he has the gift of sight...
就如同他無法回到未出生時
any more than he can be unborn.
肏
Fuck.
漢娜
Hannah!
別過來
Stay away from me.
漢娜 -別過來
- Hannah. - Stay away from me.
我們得走了 -我叫你別過來
- We need to go. - I said stay away!
好了 沒事了 請享用餐點吧
There. Everything is all right. Please enjoy your meal.
漢娜
Hannah?
你做了什麼事?
What have you done?
我怎麼了?
What's happening to me?
好了...
Here, here, here.
沒事 你安全了
It's all right. You're safe now.
別碰她
Leave her alone.
拉克哈先生 她已經被你弄得夠煩了
Haven't you upset her enough, Mr. Lockhart?
請送病人回房
Please, escort the patient back to his room.
我不是他媽的病人
I am not a fucking patient!
來啊
Come on!
受夠這裡的跋腳跟老人了嗎?
Had enough of cripples and old people?
來找我試試看啊
Try it with me!
夠了 拉克哈先生
That's enough! Mr. Lockhart...
我看得出你非常沮喪
I can see you're extremely upset.
你來我的辦公室吧
Why don't you come with me to my office...
我們可以討論你的疑惑
and we can discuss whatever's on your mind.
不要
No.
我們就在這裡談
We're gonna talk about it right here.
在所有人面前談
In front of everybody.
我認為這樣不太好
I don't think that's a good idea.
他在害大家生病
He's making you sick.
這個地方會害你生病
This place is making you sick!
病原在水裡
It's in the water.
拉克哈先生
Mr. Lockhart.
我看到跟木乃伊一樣的屍體
I saw the bodies dried up like mummies!
看看你們
Look at you people!
你們在掉牙齒
Your teeth are falling out!
你們快死了卻不自覺
You're dying, and you can't even see it.
可是我是來治療的
But I'm here for the cure.
根本沒有療法
There is no cure!
你們看不出來嗎?
Don't you see?
就是他害大家生病的
He's the one that is making you sick!
你們沒有問題
There's nothing wrong with you people!
如果我是你 就不會這這麼做
I wouldn't do that, if I were you.
你們沒有問題
There's nothing wrong with you.
對
Yes.
Yes!
就是這樣
That's it!
站起來吧
Stand up!
快點
Come on!
對
Yes!
站起來
Stand up!
他在害你們生病
He is making you sick!
對 這樣就對了 來吧
Yes, that's it. Come on.
這樣就對了
That's it!
你們沒生病
There's nothing wrong with you!
我生病了 -我生病了
I am not well.
我生病了
你們要幹嘛?
What are you doing?
他媽的放開我
Get the fuck off me!
不...
No. No, no!
放開我
Get off me.
救救我 救我
Help me! Help!
潘柏
Pembroke.
潘柏先生
他們把你怎麼了?
What have they done to you?
把我怎麼了?
Done to me?
我從來沒感覺這麼好過
I've never felt better.
拉克哈先生 放輕鬆
Relax, Mr. Lockhart.
療程很快就結束了
It'll all be over soon.
沒錯 了不起的生物
Ah, yes. Remarkable creatures.
在別的地方 這生物頂多才活十來年
Anywhere else on the planet, this species lives a dozen years, at most.
但在我們的含水土層裡
Here, in our aquifer...
它們能活三百年
they can live 300.
就人類的生理而言
For the human physiology...
水對人來說挺毒的 你也發現了
the effect of the water can be quite toxic as you have discovered.
但經過適當的過濾就沒問題了
Unless, of course, it is properly filtered.
這是男爵發明的療程
The baron devised the process.
利用他土地所屬的人民實臉
Using the bodies of peasants that belonged to his land...
他設法將水蒸餾至...
he managed to distill the water...
活絡生命的精髓
to its life-giving essence.
他當然為了他的聰明才智 付出慘痛代價
Of course, he paid a terrible price for his ingenuity.
他唯一的錯...
His only mistake...
就是利用了非自願的人當對象
was to use subjects who were unwilling.
幸好 時代不一樣了
Luckily, times have changed.
這兩百年是人類史上 生產力最旺盛的時期
The last 200 years have been the most productive in human history.
世人擺脫上帝
Man rid himself of God...
擺脫階級以及賦予人類意義的一切
of hierarchy, of everything that gave him meaning...
最後只剩下崇拜自我野心的空虛感
until he was left worshiping the empty altar of his own ambition.
這是他們來此的原因
That is why they come.
他們像你一樣
Men like you.
拉克哈先生 你說得很對
You're quite right, Mr. Lockhart.
沒有人離開過
No one ever leaves.
但你搞錯了 是沒人想要離開
What you fail to understand is that no one wants to.
知道人類困境的療法是什麼嗎?
Do you know what the cure for the human condition is?
疾病
Disease.
因為唯有如此才有尋求療法的希望
Because only then is there hope for a cure.
我不懂
I don't understand.
多年來 我一在想保護你
For so many years, I've tried to protect you...
遠離外界的污穢
from the impurities of the outside world.
但諷刺的是
But ironically, it is your friend Mr. Lockhart
我們反倒得感謝你朋友拉克哈先生
who we have to thank.
你現在是女人了
You're a woman now.
可是我生病了
But I'm not well.
我永遠都會在這裡照顧你
And I will always be here to take care of you.
她醒了
She's awake now.
你讓我以為我有一天會離開這裡
You made me believe I could leave here one day.
怎麼會有人想要離開?
Why would anybody wanna leave?
“范海克莫”
什麼事?
What is it?
來
Come.
這是什麼地方?
What is this place?
這裡就是你生命的起點
This is where you began.
我不想要
I don't want to.
你知道...
You know...
你跟她在新婚之夜一模一樣
you look just like she did on her wedding night.
“她不曉得”
村民在那一晚把她從我身邊奪走
The night they took her from me.
村民挖出胎兒並扔進含水土層
The villagers cut out the fetus and threw it in the aquifer.
那孩子沒死
The child survived.
拜託不要 -別怕
Please don't. Don't be frightened.
我們很快又是一家人了
Soon we'll be a family again.
這是我們永遠的宿命
The way we were always meant to be.
沒事 我妹一開始也抗拒過
It's all right. My sister was also somewhat resistant, at first.
但不久之後 她就愛上了
But after a while, she grew to like it.
我們不斷努力想製造純潔之物
We tried so many times to make something pure.
那就是你 我的愛
That something was you, my love.
現在...
And now...
我們可以再度開始
we can begin again.
我等好久了
I've waited so long.
太久了
So long.
他會占據你 好嗎?
He will have you. Yes?
好
Yes.
你不能永遠把她困在這裡
You can't keep her here forever.
不能嗎?
No?
你覺得她到外面會變成什麼樣?
And what do you think would become of her in your world?
一大堆你們這種人
People like you come to me in droves
帶著可有可無的生活來找我
with your disposable lives.
她是你女兒
She's your daughter.
你又愛過什麼了?
And what have you ever loved, hmm?
你做過什麼犧牲嗎?
What have you ever sacrificed?
這就是外面世界的貢獻
This is what the outside world has to offer.
你說得對
You're right.
不要
No.
失火了
Fire. Fire!
我經營的一切都是為了她
Everything I have built has been for her.
你以為我會讓你這種人渣毀了嗎?
You think I would let someone like you destroy that?
爸
Dad?
漢娜
Hannah.
“今日探訪時間已過”
很壯觀吧?
Magnificent, isn't it?
拉克哈
Lockhart!
我們該走了
It's time to go.
你沒事吧? -老天
- Are you okay? - Jesus Christ.
別激動
Easy, easy.
拉克哈?
Lockhart?
不會吧
My God.
你做了什麼?
What have you done?
潘柏呢?
Where's Pembroke?
他走了
He's gone.
他走了是什麼意思?
What do you mean "gone"?
上車
Get in the car.
你是來辦事的 記得嗎?
You came here to perform a task, remember?
現在給我上車
Now get in the car.
你聽到我說的話了嗎?
Did you hear what I said?
你發瘋了嗎?
Have you lost your mind?
其實...
Actually...
我感覺我好多了
I'm feeling much better.
你搞什麼想去哪?
Where the hell are you going?
拉克哈 拉克哈
Lockhart! Lockhart!
翻譯:張倩茜